# Joey Chiao-Yin Hsiao

jcyhsiao@umich.edu • +1 (734) 730-0963 • http://joeyhsiao.info 4365 N. Quad, 105 S. State St., Ann Arbor, MI 48109, USA

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Computer-Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW), and Social Computing. My current topic is focused on how location-based social applications, such as people-nearby applications, hybrid community applications, sharing economy applications, can support newcomers in adapting to a new environment.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Michigan

**Doctoral Candidate in Information** 

Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt

National Taiwan University

M.S. in Computer Science

Advisor: Dr. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu

Carnegie Mellon University (Silicon Valley Campus)

Visiting Scholar Advisor: Dr. Ted Selker

National Taiwan University

B.S. in Computer Science

Ann Arbor, MI, USA 09/2015 – present

Taipei, Taiwan

09/2010 - 06/2013

Moffett Field, CA, USA

07/2012 - 09/2012

Taipei, Taiwan 09/2006 – 06/2010

# **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Peer-Reviewed Journal Articles

• Hsiao, J. C.-Y. and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). Technology to Support Immigrant Access to Social Capital and Adaptation to a New Country. To appear in *Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction*, Vol. 2, CSCW, Article 70. (acceptance rate: 25.6%).

# Peer-Reviewed Conference Proceeding Papers

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Moser, C., Schoenebeck, S., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). The Role of Demographics, Trust, Computer Self-efficacy, and Ease of Use in the Sharing Economy. In *Proc. of the 1st ACM SIGCAS Conference on Computing and Sustainable Societies (COMPASS '18)*, Article 37 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2017). People-Nearby Applications: How Newcomers Move Their Relationships Offline and Develop Social and Cultural Capital. In *Proc. of the 2017 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW '17)*, 26-40 (acceptance rate: 33%; Presenter).
- Rajan, R., **Hsiao, J. C.-Y.**, Lahoti, D., and Selker, T. (2013). "Roger that!" The Value of Adding Social Feedback in Audio-mediated Communications. In *Proc. of IFIP TC.13 International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction 2013 (INTERACT '13)*, 471-488 (acceptance rate: 31%).
- Tsai, W.-C., **Hsiao**, **J. C.-Y.**, Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., Hu, J.-C., Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Personal Soundscape. In *Proc. of International Association of Societies of Design Research 2013 (IASDR '13*), 5150-5160.

# Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2019) Fostering Immigrants' Trust in Online Local Social Exchange. To be presented at The 22nd ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW '19) Doctoral Consortium (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Dillahunt, T. R. (2017) Detecting Life Changes: Increasing Opportunities to Benefit from People-Nearby Applications. In Proc. of *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2017 (CHI EA '17)*, 1700 1707 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015) Let's Solve It Together: Introducing Crowd Workers to Friendsourcing for Improving Creative Design. Presented at *The Taiwan Computer-Human Interaction Workshop 2015 (Tai-CHI '15)* (Presenter).

# Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations (Cont.)

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015). The Price of the Priceless: Understanding Estimated Costs of Work in Friendsourcing. In *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2015 (CHI EA '15)*, 1893-1898 (Presenter).
- Tsai, W.-C., Lee, H.-C., Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Framing Design of Reminiscence Aids with Transactive Memory Theory. In The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2013 (CHI EA '13), 331-336.
- Tsai, W.-C., **Hsiao**, J. C.-Y., Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). In Search of Lost Sounds: Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Everyday Soundscape. Presented at *The ACM conference on Designing Interactive Systems 2012 (DIS '12)*.
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Jih, W.-R., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). Recognizing Continuous Social Engagement Level in Dyadic Conversation by Using Turn-taking and Speech Emotion Patterns. Presented at AAAI '12 Activity Context Representation Workshop (ACR '12) (Presenter).

#### Unpublished Theses and Research Reports

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2018). Social Network Matters: Opportunities for Technologies to Support Immigrants' Jobseeking. Field Prelim, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan.
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2017). Can People-Nearby Applications Benefit Newly-Arrived Immigrants? An Exploratory Study. *Pre-candidacy research paper*, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan.
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2012). Assessing Engagement in Conversation by Hierarchically Decomposing Emotion and Interaction. *Master's Thesis*, Dept. of Computer Science and Information Engineering (CSIE), Natl. Taiwan Univ.

#### **HONOR**

Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.

Taipei, Taiwan

201

# Graduation Representative

Was chosen as the recognized master's student for leadership and active participation in student affairs of the department

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Social Innovations Group, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

# Research Assistant

09/2015 - present

Supported Dr. Dillahunt and research of the Social Innovations Group (SIG), which is focused on designing technologies to help low-resourced populations seek employment and education (Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt)

UX Team, Intel-NTU IoX Center

Taipei, Taiwan

# Workshop Organizer

03/2015 - 05/2015

Organized the collaborative workshop on design thinking of Stanford d.school and National Taiwan University IoX Center

Research Assistant

07/2014 - 07/2015

Carried out research on user experience and natural user interface under smart environment as the only M.S. member in the team (Advisor: Dr. Bing-Yu Chen)

Collaborative & Social Computing Lab, Dept. CS, Natl. Tsing-Hua Univ.

Hsinchu, Taiwan

#### Visiting Research Assistant

07/2014 - 07/2015

Led a project on friendsourcing, aiming to understand how social capital works when a SNS user requests resources on her/his own social network (Advisor: Dr. Hao-Chuan Wang)

Taiwan Army (Mandatory Military Service)

Taichung, Taiwan

# Company Chief Consultant (Second Lieutenant)

08/2013 - 07/2014

Handled psychological consulting, human resources management, and welfare of a military company with 40+ members

Intelligent Agents Lab, Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.

Taipei, Taiwan

#### System Administrator

03/2011 - 07/2013

Managed devices and web services for 30+ lab members

#### PROFESSIONAL SERVICES Academic Events & Activities ACM MobileHCI 2019 09/2017 - Present Student Volunteer Chair TaiCHI 2015 01/2015 - 07/2015Organizing Committee 01/2014 - 07/2014OpenHCI Workshop 2014 (student-organized workshop on HCI in Taiwan) Steering Committee OpenHCI Workshop 2013 01/2013 - 07/2013Program Chair OpenHCI Workshop 2011 01/2011 - 07/2011Registration and Volunteer Chair Social Events & Activities Univ. of Michigan, School of Information 08/2018 - Present Doctoral Committee - Student Representative Annual Taiwan Night at CHI 2015 - 2018 Organizing Committee

#### Reviewer

ACM CHI 2017 - 2019; ACM CSCW 2017, 2018; ACM MobileHCI 2018; ACM TEI 2017

# Conference Student Volunteer

ACM CSCW 2018, 2019 (registered); ACM COMPASS 2018; ACM CHI 2017

| TEACHING EXPERIENCE  |             |
|--|-------------|
| Teaching Assistant/Graduate Student Instructor  School of Information, Univ. of Michigan  SI-622: Usability Testing Instructor: Prof. Joyojeet Pal   | Winter 2018 |
| School of Information, Univ. of Michigan SI-501: Contextual Inquiry Instructor: Prof. Kentaro Toyama   | Fall 2017   |
| Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ. & Dept. Design, Natl. Taiwan Univ. of Tech. and Sci.  Advanced Human-Computer Interface/User-Oriented Innovation Design Instructor: Prof. Hsien-Hui Tang & Prof. Mike Y. Chen | Spring 2013 |
| Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ. Introduction to Computer Science Instructor: Prof. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu  | Fall 2011   |
| Student Team Coach OpenHCI Workshop 2011   | 07/2011     |

# VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Autism Serves VolunteerTaipei, Taiwan $StarRain\ Service\ Association\ for\ Autism$ 02/2008-06/2013